Joy Thomas

joylol.github.io github.com/joylol linkedin.com/in/joythomas7

I am motivated to apply and grow my newly acquired passion and skills in programming in a front end web development position. I will bring to the position many years of experience in collaborating with coworkers and successfully meeting clients' needs.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks/Libraries: jQuery, Knockout.js (MVVM), Bootstrap, Jasmine

Other: Git/GitHub, Chrome Developer Tools

Projects

Feed Reader Testing - joylol.qithub.io/FE-P6-FeedReaderTesting-JT/

October 2015

• Tested the functionality of the provided Google feed reader using Jasmine

$\textbf{Neighborhood Map -} \underline{\textit{joylol.github.io/FE-P5a-Neighborhoodmap-JT/}}$

October 2015

- Built a single-page, responsive application with Knockout.js framework and hosted on GitHub Pages
- Developed a full-page map that highlights 10 top locations to visit in Dallas, TX
- Employed AJAX to Wiki API to allow the user view more information about each location

Website Optimization - *github.com/joylol/FE-P4-WebOptimization-JT*

September 2015

- Optimized critical rendering path of existing website to achieve PageSpeed Insights score above 90
- Eliminated inefficiencies in the website's scroll animation; site now scrolls at 60 frames per second

Arcade Game Clone - joylol.github.io/FE-P3-Arcadegame-JT/

August 2015

- Displayed a clone of the classic game, Frogger, using HTML5
- Coded player, enemies, and other game entities in JavaScript's object-oriented pseudo-classical style

Experience

Arlington ISD - High School Science Teacher

Arlington, TX | 2012 - 2015

- Designed and executed engaging science lessons, activities, tests and labs for 160+ high school students per year
- Increased the number of students achieving advance ratings on end of course exams each year by 20%

UT Southwestern - Research Technician II

Dallas, TX | 2010 - 2011

- Cultured bacteria, extracted protein, and ran various lab protocols as member of 4 person lab team
- Successfully visualized the binding of a protein (ChREBP) by applying lab techniques precisely and efficiently

Church in Dallas - Outreach Coordinator

Dallas, TX | 2006 - 2009

- Collaborated with colleagues to plan, market, and carry out Bible studies, lectures, and many other community events
- Led over 15 Bible studies each week

Education

Udacity - Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

October 2015

University of North Texas - M.S. Library Science

May 2011

Bible Truth and Church Service Training - 2 year program graduate

December 2005

University of Texas at Arlington - B.S. Biology - Magna Cum Laude

December 2003

Honors and Activities

 $\bullet \quad \text{N.N. Libraries of Medicine Health Information Outreach Scholarship} - \textit{Recipient}$

October 2010

• Arlington Reads Literacy Tutor - Volunteer

January 2012 - April 2012